Touma!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻(とうま)！
（上条(かみじょう)）うん？
Come out, one of the twelve disciples...
（ｱﾝｼﾞｪﾚﾈ）
来たれ　十二使徒のひとつ
debt collector, eradicator of magicians, and lowly servant!
徴税吏にして 魔術師を討ち滅ぼす
卑賤(ひせん)なるしもべよ！
インデックス！
Index!
Damn it!
くそ！
Sister Angelene! You...
シスター･アンジェレネ！
貴様は…
ち… 違います　私じゃ…
N-No, that wasn't me!
ＣＴＲＴＴＯＰ　ＡＯ
C-T-R, T-T-O-P, A-O.
That was sloppy.
ずさんだね
You didn't pay much attention to the exterior,
外側に対して気が回っていないから
簡単に割り込まれるんだよ
so it was easy to interfere.
Spell intercept?!
強制詠唱(スペルインターセプト)？
（笛の音）
退却命令ですか
An order to retreat?
Sister Angelene.
シスター･アンジェレネ！
Y-Yes!
（ｱﾝｼﾞｪﾚﾈ）
は… はい
Now do you understand?
（建宮(たてみや)）
これで分かったろうよ
（建宮）
これが 十字教内最大宗派
ローマ正教の裏のやり方よ
This is how the largest Christian Church,
the Roman Catholic Church, does their dirty work!
～♪
#04 Sheol Fear
Demon Killer's Voice
（ステイル）
その男の
言っていることが―
If everything this man told us was true,
全て事実だとしても―
Orsola Aquinas will not be executed immediately.
オルソラ＝アクィナスは
すぐには殺されないだろうね
They have their own circumstances.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
ヤツらにはヤツらの事情がある
What circumstances?
事情って何だよ？
The decryption of The Book of the Law may be a threat to the Roman Catholic Church,
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
「法の書」の解読は
ローマ正教にとって脅威だが
but Orsola Aquinas has never sinned.
オルソラ＝アクィナスには
何の罪もない
They can't simply murder believers of God's Gospel, after all.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
神の教えを信じる者を
殺(あや)めてはならないからね
Then why did the Amakusa Church try to stop Orsola's assassination?
じゃ なんで天草(あまくさ)式は―
オルソラの暗殺を
止めようとしたんだ？
Because there's an exception.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
例外があるからね
"One may not murder a believer of God's Gospel."
“神の教えを信じる者を
殺めてはならない”
An interpretation of this rule is that those who have been kicked out of the church
このルールにのっとるなら
教会から追い出された人間は―
can be murdered as non-believers of God's Gospel.
神の教えを信じない者として
殺してもよいことになるんだ
In other words, she'll bear the label "enemy of God."
（建宮）
つまり そいつは―
“神の敵”というレッテルを
貼り付けられるってことよ
The power a grimoire contains cannot bring happiness.
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
魔道書の力なんて
誰も幸せにしないのでございますよ
It brings about nothing but conflict to those around it.
それを巡って 争いしか
生まなかったのでございます
Like hell!
ふっざけんな
残念だけど もう終わりさ
僕たちの出る幕は もうないんだ
I'm afraid to say this, but it's already over.
It's out of our hands now.
なんだよ それ！
人の命を何だと思ってるんだ！
What's that supposed to mean?
What do you take a person's life for?!
This occurred within the Roman Catholic Church,
and they will judge the case with their own rules.
これは
ローマ正教で起きた事件を―
彼らのルールで
裁いているにすぎない
Or could it be that you wish to save her, even if it means war?
それとも 君は戦争を起こしてでも
彼女を助ける気かい？
それは…
Well...
Hey, kid. Don't get so depressed.
（建宮）
ああ 少年　そこまでヘコむなって
Unlike the Church of England,
we have a huge reason to fight them.
イギリス清教に戦う理由はなくても
こっちには大ありなのよな
We'll invade their hideout and rescue Orsola along with our idiots.
ちょっくら
連中のアジトまで おジャマして
ウチのバカどもを救出するついでに
オルソラ嬢も助けてやんよ
Do you plan on going alone?
まさか
１人で行くとか言う気かい？
フフッ… それしかねえなら
それで行くしかねえってのよ
If that's the only option, then I have no choice but to go.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）話は決まったようだね
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）うん？
It seems like it's been decided.
We'll split up and hide ourselves.
僕たちも解散して 姿を隠そう
Return to Academy City with Index.
君はインデックスと共に
学園都市へ戻れ
Okay.
（上条）分かった
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）あっ…
Oh...
それと ひとつだけ
聞いておきたいことがあるんだ
There's one more thing I need to ask you.
何だよ？
What is it?
That cross I gave you...
前に 僕が君にやった十字架
今 君は持っていないようだが
You don't seem to have it with you right now.
あっ… 悪い
オルソラに預けちまったままだった
S-Sorry, I gave it to Orsola.
Was it expensive?
あれ そんなに高い物だったのか？
No, but its value was in you holding it...
いや　君が持っていることに
価値があったんだが
まあいい
Well, whatever.
You don't need it anymore.
どうせ もう
今の君には必要ない物だろうからね
Let's go.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）行くぞ
（上条）あ… ああ
What should I do?
（上条）
どうすればいいんだろうな
Wasn't there something I could've done?
俺にも 何かできることが
あったんじゃないか？
This is a quarrel between magicians.
これは魔術師の問題なんだから
You don't need to force yourself to get involved.
当麻が
ムリに関わらなくてもいいんだよ
You think?
そっかな
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
今までが おかしかったんだよ
You've always been weird.
No one can solve every problem that appears before them by themselves.
目の前で起きた問題を 何でも
自分で解決できる人間はいないよ
Right...
（上条）
そっか
Oh, yeah.
（上条）あっ そうだ
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）うん？
Our fridge is empty.
冷蔵庫の中が空っぽだ
I'll go find a convenience store and buy a few things.
ちょっとコンビニ探して
適当に何か買ってくる
コンビニなら
みんなで一緒に行けばいいかも
We should all go together, then.
フゥ… 場所は分かってるのかい？
Do you know where it is?
I don't.
別に　その辺 走り回ってれば
見つけられるだろう
But if I run around, I'll eventually find one.
"The Church of Orsola"?
（上条）
オルソラ教会？
Yes.
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）
はい　オルソラ＝アクィナスは―
Orsola Aquinas managed to spread God's Gospel to three pagan countries
３か国もの異教地で
神の教えを広めたって功績があって
自分の名を冠する教会を
建てる許可を特別にいただいたんで
and received special permission to construct a church bearing her own name.
I think it was somewhere around here.
確か この辺りだったと思いますよ
Sheesh, you shouldn't waste our time.
…たく
手間をかけさせちゃダメでしょう
Unfortunately, we don't have the time to play around with your games.
残念ながら あなたの遊びに
つきあってる暇なんてないんです
If you understand, shut up and accept your punishment—
分かってんなら
おとなしく処刑を…
Are you listening?!
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）
聞いてんですか？
I'm asking you a question, damn it!
“聞いてんですか”
つってんでしょうがよ
こら！
（蹴る音）
At any rate, it seems you don't have many friends to rely on.
それにしても 頼れるお友達が 随分
少なかったみたいじゃないですか
To think that you'd ask the Amakusa Church you had just met for help...
まさか
現地で出会った天草式なんぞに―
協力を求めちまうとはね
The Amakusa Church, the Church of England...
天草式だの イギリス清教だの
It's ridiculous for those churches to even call themselves Christian.
あんなのが十字教を名乗るのは
おこがましいってなもんですよ
You're in this current state because you put your precious life in their filthy hands.
そんなもんに
大事な命を預けちまうから―
こんな目に遭っちまうんです
It didn't take much to fool them and have them bring you to us.
ちょっと手なずければ
簡単にダマされて
獲物を持ってきてくれんですから
You... fooled...
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
ダマされて？
You fooled... them?
あの方たちは…
ダマされたのでございますか？
Yes.
So... you weren't cooperating with them, but fooling them... instead?
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
あなたたちに協力したのではなく…
ダマされて…
（床を突く音）
そんなのどっちでもいいでしょうが
Who cares about that?!
You're useless if you hand what you're supposed to protect to the enemy.
守るべき者を てめえが
その手で敵の手に送り返しちゃ―
世話ないってなもんですよ
I see.
そうでございますか
ンッ… な… なに笑ってんですか
W-What are you smiling about?
I see...
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
そうですか
So... I'm actually smiling right now...
私は今 笑ってるのでございますね
I just had an epiphany...
なんとなく
思い知らされたのでございますよ
...as to what the Roman Catholic Church really is.
私たちローマ正教の本質が―
どういうものなのかを
The others act based on their beliefs.
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
彼らは信じることによって
行動するのでございますよ
Believing in people, and believing in their thoughts...
人を信じ 思いを信じ
その気持ちを信じて―
Believing in those feelings, they will probably go to any lengths to pursue whatever they seek.
どこまでも駆けつけてくれるので
ございましょう
In comparison, all we do is act upon our doubts.
それに対して 私たちは
疑うことでしか行動できない
Just how ugly is that?
それの なんと醜いことか
If you really want to die, then just get it over with!
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）
そんなに死にたいなら
お好きなようにしちまってください
At the very least, you should die
cursing those who brought you here.
せいぜい 自分を
こんな目に遭わせちまった―
あのバカどもを恨みながら
死にゆけばいいんですよ
And what exactly...
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）一体…
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）ハッ…
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
何を
恨めばよいのでございましょうか
...should I curse them for?
What?
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）
なに？
They had no reason to fight in the first place.
彼らには もともと 戦う理由など
なかったのでございますよ
Even so, they came running for me, a stranger.
それでも 見ず知らずの私のために
駆けつけてきてくれたので
ございます
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
ほら　これ以上に魅力的な贈り物が
See?
Is there anything more wonderful than that in this world?
この世界のどこに
あるというのでございましょう
They've given me such a wonderful gift.
こんなにも すばらしい贈り物を
くださった方々に―
So what exactly should I curse them for?
私は一体 何を
恨めばよいというのでございますか
まさか 結界が壊された？
くそ… どこの組織だってんですか
No way... the barrier was breached?
Damn it. Which organization did that?
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）
フン… ただのド素人が なんで…
I was wondering how a rookie could manage to do this...
…とは思っていたんですがね
But it seems you have some sort of absolute power against the barrier.
結界に対して
絶対の力を持つ何かがあると
Am I right?
そういうわけですか
I'm curious...
（上条）
一応 聞くけどよ　もう
ごまかすつもりはねえんだな？
you don't plan on fooling me again, do you?
Fool you? About what?
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）
ごまかす？　何を？
Can't you tell from the situation? Sheesh.
この状況を見て
分かんないんですか？ …たく
Last I saw, the Church of England retreated, so what on Earth are you?
どうやら イギリス清教は
逃げ帰っちまったようですけど
あなたは一体 何なんですか？
Look, this is your last chance.
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）
ほら　これが最後のチャンスです
You know very well what you should do, right?
自分が何をすべきかぐらい
分かっちまってますよね？
Yeah.
（上条）
そうだな
確かに これが最後のチャンスだ
This is indeed my last chance.
I know that very well.
（上条）よく分かってるよ
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）だったら…
Then...
き… 貴様… 何のマネだ これは！
You bastard... what the hell do you think you're doing?!
（上条）
“何をすべきか”だと？
You asked me what I should do, didn't you?
Taking me for a fool...
ナメやがって…
助けるに決まってんだろうが！
I'm obviously rescuing her!
You're very interesting.
面白いですよ あなた
What can you do here, all by yourself?
この状況で あなた１人に
何が どこまでできんのか
Why don't you show us?!
見せてもらうとしましょうか
Good grief.
まったく…
勝手に始めないでほしいね
Don't just start things on your own.
Stiyl!
（上条）ステイル！
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）イ… イギリス清教？
T-The Church of England?!
Impossible... this is an exclusive problem of the Roman Catholic Church!
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）
バカな… これは
ローマ正教内だけの問題なんですよ
内政干渉と見なされちまうのが
分かんないんですか？
Surely you understand that this will be considered disruption of our internal affairs!
ああ
残念ながら それは適用されない
Unfortunately, that is not the case.
Look at Orsola Aquinas's chest.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
オルソラ＝アクィナスの胸を見ろ
There lies the cross of the Church of England.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
そこにイギリス清教の十字架が
かけられているだろう
それを誰かにかけてもらう行為は
そのまま―
By having someone put the necklace on you,
you gain protection from the Church of England.
イギリス清教の庇護(ひご)を得る
つまり…
In other words, Orsola Aquinas is no longer of the Roman Catholic Church, but of us, the Church of England.
オルソラ＝アクィナスは
ローマ正教ではなく―
僕たちイギリス清教の
一員になったということさ
I see...
そっか　それで…
That's why...
Do you really think that sort of logic will work?!
そんな詭弁(きべん)が
通じるとでも思ってんですか？
Not in the slightest.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
思っちゃいないね　だが―
But for you, the Roman Catholic Church,
to have sole discretion in her interrogation...
君たちローマ正教の一存のみで
彼女を審問にかけるというなら…
The Church of England can't just stand back and watch.
イギリス清教は これを黙って
見過ごすわけにはいかないんだよ
Furthermore, how dare you point a weapon at her.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
それと よくも
あの子に刃(やいば)を向けてくれたものだ
Do I look like the kind of person who'd be kind and forgiving enough to let that go?
この僕が それを見過ごすほど―
甘く優しい人格を
しているとでも思ったか
クッ…
１人が２人に増えたところで…
Just because we're now against two instead of one—
（建宮）
２人で済むとか
思ってんじゃねえのよ
Don't go thinking this'll end with just two.
I'm sure you don't need to hear the reason why I'm fighting, right?
俺が戦わなきゃいかん理由は
わざわざ問うまでもねえよな
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）クッ…
（上条）建宮…
Tatemiya...
（建宮）
せっかく
イギリス清教の連中と話し合って
I had just finished conversing with the Church of England.
We were planning on taking care of everything before you came, too...
お前さんが動く前に―
決着つける手はずを
整えようとしていたのに
You're more stupid than I thought.
お前さん 想像以上のバカだよな
Not that I dislike stupid people that are fun to watch...
まあ 見ていて楽しいバカは
嫌いじゃねえが
Like I said...
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
だから 決着は私がつけるから―
I even told you that I'd take care of things so you didn't have to worry, Touma.
当麻は気にしなくていいよって
言ったのに
Index!
インデックス！
But we have no choice now.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
でも こうなっちゃったら
しかたがないよね
Let's rescue Orsola Aquinas, Touma.
助けよう 当麻
オルソラ＝アクィナスを
私たちの手で
With our own hands.
Yeah!
Kill them!
殺せ！
オルソラ　体は大丈夫か？
Orsola, are you okay?
Yes, this is nothing.
ええ　こんなもの
全然 平気でございますわ
なんだよ　戦う理由なんて―
What the hell...
The reason to fight is so easy to understand.
こんなに分かりやすいものが
あったんじゃねえか
（五和）うん
（上条）サ… サンキュー
T-Thank you!
（土御門(つちみかど)）
ニャッハー！
感謝 感激 感動の極みって
とこですかい？　神裂(かんざき)ねーちん
You couldn't be more thankful, grateful, and moved, huh, Kanzaki-neechin?
（神裂）土御門…
（土御門）いやぁ 良かったじゃん
Tsuchimikado.
Well, isn't that dandy?
You now know your old friends didn't kidnap Orsola in order to use The Book of the Law for their own interests.
かつての仲間たちが
私欲で「法の書」を使うために―
オルソラを
誘拐したわけじゃないって分かって
What about you?
（神裂）
そちらは終わったのですか？
I'm fairly certain you had planned on using all this commotion to steal The Book of the Law.
おおかた この機に乗じて
「法の書」の原典を―
横から かすめ取ろうという
算段だったのでしょうが
I'm sure you have a good idea of what's happening.
（土御門）
事の顛末(てんまつ)は 大体 知ってんだろう？
The Amakusa Church didn't steal The Book of the Law.
天草式は「法の書」なんか
盗んじゃいなかった
It was a false accusation the Roman Catholic Church made.
ローマ正教が仕組んだ冤罪(えんざい)だった
なら そもそも日本に「法の書」を
持ち込む必要なんかねえですたい
It follows that there was no reason to bring the authentic Book of the Law to Japan, no?
The Book of the Law that was brought to Japan was a fake.
日本に持ち込んだ「法の書」は
ニセモノ
I'm assuming the original still resides deep within the Vatican Library.
原典は今も
バチカン図書館の奥の奥だろうよ
…で 満足できたのかい？
Well? Are you satisfied?
Yes. With them around...
ええ　彼らがいるなら―
The Amakusa Church can walk down the correct path without my guidance.
私がいなくても
天草式は正しき道を進めるでしょう
（蹴る音）
（ｼｽﾀｰたち）ウワッ！
ハッ…
だ… 大丈夫でございますか？
A-Are you okay?
Yeah...
くそ！
Damn it!
（建宮）ああ？
（ｼｽﾀｰ）ハアッ！
Why am I not getting any action?!
この俺に つまらん場面を
見せつけんじゃねえのよ！
Stop!
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）よせ！
（建宮）あっ…
Now isn't the time to approach her.
今のあの子に
不用意に近づくんじゃない
Her power will be weakened if you do.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
僕たちが近づいては
あの子の強さを奪ってしまうんだ
（ｼｽﾀｰたち）
ハアッ！
（建宮）
な… 何なのよ？　こりゃ
What the hell?
It's a song that uses the contents of all 103,000 grimoires to relentlessly expose the contradictions in their teachings:
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
あの歌は 10万3,000冊の
あらゆる知識を使って―
教義の中の矛盾点を
徹底的に糾弾する“魔滅の声(シェオールフィア)”さ
"Sheol Fear."
For those who live their lives according to doctrine, you could call it their worst enemy.
教義というＯＳに従って
動いている人間にとっては―
正に天敵と言っていい
Listening to it causes their spirits to temporarily crumble, much like a jigsaw puzzle.
あれを聞けば 一時的とはいえ
人格をパズルのように崩されるぞ
魔道書は
単に読むだけの物じゃない
Grimoires are not just for reading.
She can use those grimoires even though she has no magical abilities.
あの子は 魔力がなくとも
魔道書を使いこなす
There probably isn't anyone else more fit for the role of a grimoire library.
魔道書図書館として―
あれほど ふさわしい人材は
ほかにいないだろうね
（蹴る音）
しっかし まあ―
But man... why didn't you use a
trump card like that from the start?
あんな隠し球があるんなら
なんで最初から使わんかったのよ？
That attack works on group mentality to pierce through mental barriers.
あの攻撃は―
集団心理ってやつに働きかけて
心の防壁を突破する
So the question then becomes,
"how pure is this group mentality?"
だから 問題になるのが
集団心理の純度でね
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
君らとの戦闘では
僕や上条当麻が障害となって―
When we fought against you, Kamijou and I acted as obstacles,
lowering the purity in which the chant could be activated.
純度が下がり
うまく機能しなかったってわけだ
（建宮）
あんなもん食らってたら
シャレにならんかったのよ
I'd hate to get hit by the likes of that.
（ｼｽﾀｰ）マズイかも
（ｼｽﾀｰ）どうする？
（ｼｽﾀｰ）
でも 逃げるわけには…
（ｱﾝｼﾞｪﾚﾈ）
そそ… そうですよ
T-That's right...
騒いでんじゃないですよ！
バカみたいに見えちまいますよ
Stop being babies!
We'll look like idiots otherwise.
Especially you, Sister Angelene.
特に シスター･アンジェレネ！
（ｱﾝｼﾞｪﾚﾈ）
し… しかし シスター･アニェーゼ
B-But Sister Agnese, it's been over ten minutes since the battle began.
戦闘が始まってから
10分以上たっています
We still outnumber them heavily even if we count Orsola with them!
オルソラを数に入れても
あれだけの人数差ですよ
This isn't normal!
こんなのは普通じゃありません
（爆発音）
ウワッ！
ほ… ほら
L-Look!
（ｱﾝｼﾞｪﾚﾈ）
今の爆発だって
どちらが放ったものなのですか？
Which side caused that explosion?!
Maybe they're going on the offensive!
もしかしたら
ヤツらが攻勢に回っているのかも
わ… 私たちも動きましょう
少しでも人数が多いほうが…
L-Let's fight as well!
We need all the numbers we can get...
ハァ…
Then I relieve you of your position as my escort.
ならば 私の護衛の任は解きます
戦列に加わっちまってください
Please go join the ranks.
は… はい
絶対に連中を逃がしません
Y-Yes! We won't let them go, no matter what!
They can't run...
逃げられやしませんよ
逃げられるはずがありません
There's no way they can run.
That's just how this damned world works...
そういうふうに
できちまってるんです
この くそったれの世界は
Focus on attacking; do not worry about defense!
攻撃を重視！　防御を軽視！
Be prepared to die in order to defeat our Lord's enemies!
玉砕覚悟で
我らが主の敵を殲滅(せんめつ)せよ！
何らかの魔術攻撃…
Is that some sort of magical attack?
ま… まさか…
N-No way...
“魔滅の声(シェオールフィア)”を回避するために？
They did that to avoid Sheol Fear?
～♪
Next Episode
（上条）
最後の戦いが始まった
The final battle has begun.
雪崩のように続く攻撃に
俺たちは追い詰められていく
The avalanche of attacks has pushed us into a corner.
果たして 活路はあるのか？
Is there a way for us to emerge victorious?
次回 「蓮の杖(ロータスワンド)」
Next Time: "Lotus Wand."
When science and magic cross paths, this epic will begin!
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる